

DANH NGUYEN

Address: 2250 NW 94th Way, Fort Lauderdale, FL

Phone: 954-610-6301

Email: dcnguyen93@yahoo.com
Personal Website: https://www.danhnguyen.it

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danh-nguyen-45562712b

SUMMARY

Cloud engineer with experience in building scalable, cost-efficient Azure solutions for business needs. At Mindtree (supporting Microsoft), I was involved in tooling that tracked and optimized high-cost Azure resources across multiple internal subscriptions. At Nation Safe Drivers, I delivered analytics for nationwide towing operations using modern frameworks and UI. I'm based in Sunrise, FL and prefer working remotely but am willing to relocate to join new talents.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer, Freelance Software Development

Oct 2023 - Present

- Created and maintained custom professional Next.js websites for clients in the health and beauty industry.
- Developed multi-lingual Al-driven solution for answering calls, FAQ handling, appointment booking/cancellation with salon's existing scheduling system.
- Integrated Twilio Voice to transfer callers to live operators on an as need basis.
- Created REST API Azure Functions in .NET for Conversational AI Agent to use as tools for managing appointments for salon.

Full Stack Software Engineer II, Nation Safe Drivers

Jul 2021 - Oct 2023

- Responsible for tailoring the Client Qore platform for new clients, aligning the portal's
 appearance with the client's branding and ensuring accurate data feeds into the reporting
 modules.
- Provided support for the API used for handling roadside assistance requests.
- Participate in Agile rituals such as daily stand-ups, sprint planning, backlog refinement, and retrospectives to ensure efficient delivery and continuous improvement of solutions.

Software Engineer, LTIMindtree

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

- Proactively monitored and troubleshooted crawler Web Jobs based in C# to ensure it ran smoothly.
- Implemented parallel API calls to speed up data collection across multiple subscriptions.
- Utilized Application Insights to monitor and track events throughout the duration of a crawl to enable prompt resolutions for failures.
- Implemented mechanisms to recover from last known failure reducing the need to redo work, saving time and resource.
- Analyzed and optimized slow-running queries using execution plans and query tuning suggestions to improve responsiveness of reports.
- Participate in daily SCRUM meetings to prioritize tasks as well as to identify and unblock any impediments throughout sprint cycle.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering

Florida Atlantic University

May 2014 - Dec 2018

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Programming Languages: C#, JavaScript, T-SQL Libraries/Frameworks: React, Node, NextJS

Tools/Platforms: Git, VS Code, Visual Studio 2022, Microsoft Azure

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server